The next merengue partnering basic steps that everyone has to has to master.
Begin in close position.
Could be an open position but it's much better lead from this close position.
Now what we are going to do is go into our Merengue and I'm going to take my partner actually instead of in a circle, I'm going to take her side, side and forward back.
So we're going to come we're going to start the step and one, two ,three, four, five, six, seven and one, two ,three, four, five, six, seven and one, two ,three, four, five, six, seven and one, two ,three, four, five, six, seven and one, two ,three, four, five, six, seven and one more basic three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Again in general the leader is using his frame.
The leader is traveling and he's taking his dance partner with him.
He's using his whole body and I'm not just using my hand and not just trying to make her go places by pushing her around.
I'm actually using my arm.
Any part that's connected.
I'm not just connected on the back.
I have a point of connection on the back but I also have a point of connection right here, where my arm is touching the side of her body.
So if I want her to move to the side, I'm using my arm to bring her side.
I'm also opening up this arm a little wider than I normally would and with that she's stepping right with me, right on time.
Now to switch it's a little tricky because we're staying on the same rhythm we're going left, right, left, right, left, right and then to switch to front back it's the same thing I may use my left hand a little bit more to lead it and coming back I'm using about fifty fifty.
My right and my left.
Again it's just using your frame, having a good connection.
Those are the major, major parts in these types of basic merengue steps.